Hello I'm Neil and I'm Georgie welcome to Real easyy English You can find a worksheet and transcript for this episode on our website BBC Learning English.com. .
Hi Georgie how are you I'm very well thank you Neil something that made me very happy yesterday was that my housemate made me a delicious meal it was very spicy
Well we're talking about spicy food today Yes spicy food is food that makes your mouth hot and sometimes it can be painful Neil
I like spicy food what about you Yeah I really like spicy food I think well it has,
A lot of flavor and it can make you actually feel good when you eat spicy food it can kind of lift your mood
Yeah, I agree actually spicy food really makes you feel alive the food that my housemate made for me yesterday was jerk chicken which she put on the barbecue,
And it really had a kick, so if something has a kick, it means that it's a little bit spicy so we had some mayonnaise with it to kind of cool it down
Yeah, good idea sometimes, When you eat really spicy food or hot food,
Some we say hot food, and it doesn't mean the temperature always it means spicy when you have spicy food or hot food.
It can make it feel like your mouth is on fire.
Very true.
Have you always liked spicy food or was it something you had to learn to love, I think so.
I think I've always liked spicy food, have always eaten lots of Indian curries or Mexican food or Caribbean food
Like your jerk chicken yeah.
I remember going on holiday with my family in Spain and they have a dish there made of peppers and some of them are very mild so they aren't Very spicy.
But some of them really have a kick, and you don't know which one is going to be really spicy.
So it was quite, it was almost like an exciting game.
So I've always enjoyed spice.
Okay, so Georgie, you can eat spicier food now than when you were younger.
Yes, now Neil, what's the spiciest meal you've ever eaten well.
I was traveling in Southeast Asia, and there was something on a menu in a restaurant or bar I was in called
The Spicy sausage salad.
And.
They weren't lying it was so spicy, it felt almost like somebody had attacked my tongue Oh
No, was your mouth on fire my mouth my whole head was on fire and it took a long time and lots of water
Or before I felt normal again, does water help I don't know, I I needed to try something.
I think sometimes milk can help, but I don't know if there if there's anything else that can help,
But sometimes you really need something to cool down Yeah how about you Georgie, what's the hottest thing that you've ever eaten Well,
It wasn't a meal but I used to work in a restaurant and there was a chef there who had three bottles of hot sauce with different levels of spice?
And we were all trying it, everyone that worked there and the spiciest one was so hot it was so spicy,
It my mouth was completely on fire, it was horrible, I actually didn't enjoy that everyone was sweating crying I don't think anyone enjoyed The experience.
Time now to recap the vocabulary we've heard in this episode starting with spicy If something is spicy,
It makes your mouth feel hot and that can be uncomfortable or even painful We can also describe food as hot Now hot is not always about the temperature.
It can also mean spicy If food is spicy, we can say it has a kick.
Now, Georgie said she has some Jamaican jerk chicken.
That had a kick it was spicy If you eat something that's really spicy, you could say my mouth is on fire and it means it made your mouth feel very hot.
If your mouth is on fire, you might want to cool it down with maybe a glass of water or a glass of milk That's it for this episode of real easy English but don't forget to go to our
Website where you can find a free worksheet.
And you can test yourself on what you've learned that's atbbclearningenglish.com. and we'll be back next week with another conversation in easyy English goodbye for now.